Algernon Sampson

192 College Rd. Norwich, NR2 3JA | 07735557442 | algiesampson@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/algernon-sampson

OBJECTIVE

Motivated and results-oriented software developer with 3 years of experience across a variety of green field projects as well as established codebases mainly in python, postgresql and javascript. Strong skills in AWS with experience in system design for performant applications with distributed processing for large models and internal platforms. I am looking for a position to challenge me where I can bring my experience and learn new things in a collaborative environment. I have a passion for development with new frameworks in python and javascript, here is a link to some of my smaller projects github.com/frostyfeet909/Portfolio.

EXPERIENCE

Certua Group, London

Specialist Software Developer

December 2023 - Present

- System design for large financial models to leverage parallel computing. Reducing run-time from 16hrs to 15mins.
- Implemented new pricing test harness for all future propositions in python and VBA with large scale testing.
- Built, deployed and managed key API's in fastapi with automated CI/CD in python.
- · Managing and supporting a key engineer, upskilling them in cloud services.

Data Engineer

December 2022 - December 2023

- Became owner of internal full-stack test harness and it's implementation, working with heads of department.
- · Acting as domain expert for all of insurance automating SQL and providing reports to several stakeholders.
- Integrated DevOps best practices with Docker and TeamCity to streamline multiple CI/CD pipelines.
- · Managed interns for months where they made real feature implementations to QA and backend projects.

Growth Analyst

January 2022 - December 2022

- Reduced handover time and system complexity in insurance reducing time to market from 2-3 sprints to 2-3 weeks.
- · Collaborated with our international team to see 2 insurance propositions from concept to build.
- Implemented key selenium and postman test automation, with a suite of tests covering several key applications.
- Several key presentations to senior management reviving our credit proposition.

EDUCATION

University of Nottingham

Graduated 2021

Bachelor of Science in Mathematics 1st class

- A focus on applied mathematics and scientific computation.
- Working independently to produce technical write ups and presentation to non-specialist audiences.

SKILLS

- · Highly proficient in python language, especially with microservices using fastapi and flask.
- proficiency with full-stack development with javascript and angular as a front-end.
- Usage of AWS with EC2, lambda, S3, cloudwatch, SQS.
- optimising build pipelines for CI/CD in TeamCity and GitHub Actions.
- Design for high throughput databases in PostgreSQL as well as manipulation of existing data sets with SQL.
- Organisation and time management in Agile with JIRA and Confluence writing comprehensive documentation.
- Collaboration and input into our backend, frontend, business and QA teams alongside project management.